

Contact Details

Gabriel Díaz Iturry

☐ gabriel.diaz.iturry
☐ gditurry@if.usp.br
☐ /gabo-di

Languages

Spanish: Mother tongue English: Advanced Portuguese: Fluent

Díaz Gabriel Iturry

Physicist - Data Scientist

About me Since 2012, I have worked as a scientific researcher in the area of Nonlinear Dynamics. During this period, I have acquired advanced mathematical knowledge and learned several computational skills concerning data analysis. This involves the manipulation and interpretation of data and the use of statistical tools to compare data to models. I currently work as a Self-Employed in Data Science and Physics, focused in reproducing state-of-the-art reasearch for my clients.

Experience

Feb 2021 - Present

Data Scientist, Physicist:

- Reproduce state-of-the-art reasearch.
- Deliver the models in a clear and robust interfarce for user consumption.
- Optimization using Operations Research and Heuristics methods for several projects.

Feb 2017 - Feb 2021

Researcher and Teaching Assistant, Instituto de Física, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil. Research projects include:

- Anomalous Diffusion on Classical Systems.
- Bifurcation Analysis.
- Quantum to Classical transition.

2012 - 2014

Junior Researcher and Teaching Assistant. Institute for Physics, UMSS, Physics Department. Cochabamba, Bolivia.

Education

2017 - 2021

Ph. D. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil.

2015 - 2017

M. Sc. in Physics, Universidade Estadual de São Paulo (UNESP) São Paulo, Brazil.

2009 - 2014

Bachelor in Physics, Universidad Mayor de San Simó (UMSS). Cochabamba, Bolivia.

Skills

Technical

Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Simulations, Feature Engineering, Data Analysis.

Software Development

Python, R, Julia, Fortran, Mathematica, MatLab.

Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, seaborn, matplotlib, openCV, nltk, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, sklearn, XGBoost, CatBoost.